<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<RemoteUILayout xmlns="urn:remoteui:org:layout">
	<LinearLayout orientation="vertical" width="fill_parent">
		<include href="../demos-header.layout.xml" />
		<TextView width="fill_parent" text="ScrollViews" fontSize="20"
			textColor="white" backgroundColor="ruilight" padding="5dp" />
		<LinearLayout width="fill_parent" height="fill_parent">
			<LinearLayout orientation="vertical" width="0dp"
				layoutWeight="2" height="fill_parent">
				<TextView backgroundColor="lightgray" padding="2mm"
					fontSize="20" height="wrap_content" textColor="darkgray">
					<text><![CDATA[Due to native rendering RemoteUI's ScrollViews scroll <b>smooth</b> like butter.]]></text>
				</TextView>
				<ScrollView>
					<TextView backgroundColor="white" textColor="black"
						padding="3mm" fontSize="18">
						<text>
<![CDATA[

<h2><font face="serif">A Little Cloud</font></h2>
<p><font face="serif"><i>by James Joyce</i></font></p>
<p><font face="serif">Eight years before he had seen his friend off at the North Wall and wished him
God-speed. Gallaher had got on. You could tell that at once by his travelled air,
his well-cut tweed suit, and fearless accent. Few fellows had talents like his,
and fewer still could remain unspoiled by such success. Gallaher's heart was in
the right place and he had deserved to win. It was something to have a friend
like that.</font></p>

<p><font face="serif">Little Chandler's thoughts ever since lunch-time had been of his meeting with
Gallaher, of Gallaher's invitation, and of the great city London where Gallaher
lived. He was called Little Chandler because, though he was but slightly under
the average stature, he gave one the idea of being a little man. His hands were
white and small, his frame was fragile, his voice was quiet and his manners were
refined.<br/>
He took the greatest care of his fair silken hair and moustache, and used perfume
discreetly on his handkerchief. The half-moons of his nails were perfect, and
when he smiled you caught a glimpse of a row of childish white teeth.</font></p>

<p><font face="serif">As he sat at his desk in the King's Inns he thought what changes those eight
years had brought. The friend whom he had known under a shabby and necessitous
guise had become a brilliant figure on the London Press. He turned often from
his tiresome writing to gaze out of the office window. The glow of a late autumn
sunset covered the grass plots and walks. It cast a shower of kindly golden dust
on the untidy nurses and decrepit old men who drowsed on the benches; it flickered
upon all the moving figures - on the children who ran screaming along the gravel
paths and on everyone who passed through the gardens. He watched the scene and
thought of life; and (as always happened when he thought of life) he became sad.
A gentle melancholy took possession of him. He felt how useless it was to struggle
against fortune, this being the burden of wisdom which the ages had bequeathed
to him.</font></p>

<p><font face="serif">He remembered the books of poetry upon his shelves at home. He had bought
them in his bachelor days and many an evening, as he sat in the little room off
the hall, he had been tempted to take one down from the bookshelf and read out
something to his wife. But shyness had always held him back; and so the books
had remained on their shelves. At times he repeated lines to himself and this
consoled him.</font></p>

<p><font face="serif">When his hour had struck he stood up and took leave of his desk and of his
fellow-clerks punctiliously. He emerged from under the feudal arch of the King's
Inns, a neat modest figure, and walked swiftly down Henrietta Street. The golden
sunset was waning and the air had grown sharp. A horde of grimy children populated
the street. They stood or ran in the roadway, or crawled up the steps before the
gaping doors, or squatted like mice upon the thresholds. Little Chandler gave
them no thought. He picked his way deftly through all that minute vermin-like
life and under the shadow of the gaunt spectral mansions in which the old nobility
of Dublin had roistered. No memory of the past touched him, for his mind was
full of a present joy.<br/>
...</font></p>]]>
					</text>
					</TextView>
				</ScrollView>
			</LinearLayout>
		</LinearLayout>
	</LinearLayout>
</RemoteUILayout>
